C.Y. LEE

San Jose, CA 95111

cyleex@sbcglobal.net

LinkedIn: http://www.linkedin.com/in/cyleeweb

http://www.cyleeweb.com

SPECIALTIES

Code Web Frontend & UI for Cloud and Marketing Initiatives: I am a very senior person with seasoned Fullstack Web Development skills but focused in Frontend/UI/UX arenas. I have comprehensive knowledge and experience in server-andclient side technologies, user experience/interface, visual & creative, production, management, and collaboration across Web development architecture for user-facing initiatives.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Fullstack (Frontend Web/UI Focused) Development/Support Professional -- On Contract Projects (09/2018 -)

What I do best: Client-Side UI + Template Prototyping, Dynamic Data Binding, Site + Page Performance, Team + Proj. Management -- with strong server-side knowledge and experience.

Senior Web/UI Developer for Frontend and AEM Prototyping Initiatives (MarTech) | ServiceNow (04/2017 – 09/2018)

- Contributed to Servicenow.com and Knowledge.servicenow.com in all frontend/UI solutions on daily basis.
- Built prototype components in HTML, CSS, JS with configuration and variations in collaboration with backend developers and QA engineers for AEM(6.1 & 6.4).
- Participated in rebranding efforts of Servicenow.com in 2018.
- Participated in Knowledge 18 development & implementation efforts for further development and launch in 2018.
- Provided development suggestions/guidelines often to teams in frontend/UI areas and workflow for improvement.
- Developed frontend/UI for Google Search change to AEM Search in collaboration with backend.
- Led to convert the adaptive + responsive approach (REM + % + Flex) in all aspects for responsive sufficiency.
- Shared knowledge with design team to improve Des&Dev alignment and collaboration, etc.
- Led to complete image optimization on all areas with guidelines/documentation/execution for ongoing efforts.
- Completed documentation and execution on site performance improvement of ServiceNow.com.
- Participated in K17 on-demand video library initial development for subsequent development and launch.
- Worked daily with FE/BE developers, QA Engineers and AEM Publishers for all frontend/UI support.

Fullstack (Frontend Web/UI Focused) Development/Support Professional -- On Contract Projects (11/2015 – 03/2017)

What I do best: Client-Side Template | UI Building, Dynamic Data Binding, Site | Page Performance, Team | Project | UI Management

Senior Web/UI Developer for Marketing Initiatives | FICO (Full-Time Consultant) (11/2014 – 10/2015)

- Contributed daily to myFICO.com as a team member of Engineering to UI, SEO, SEM, email landing and marketing deliverables with HTML(5)-CSS(3)-JQ-JS in .NET(ASPX+C#) and various CMS stacks including WordPress, Lithium and Oracle RNT.

Senior Web/UI Developer | Hightail formerly YouSendIt Corporation (12/2011 – 11/2014)

- Worked daily as a member of WebApp Team of Engineering with e-commerce and enterprise marketers, designers, PM and QA groups to build, implement, update and maintain web pages and components in LAMP-HTML-CSS-JQ-JS-CMS stacks for UI, SEO, SEM, email landing, business and corporate re-branding deliverables for Hightail.com.
- Resolved project and task issues for other company websites including Developer Portal.

Web/UI Developer | Fulltime Consultant | YouSendIt Corporation (08/2011 – 12/2011)

- Worked daily as a member of WebApp Team of Engineering with marketers, designers and OA groups to build, implement, update and maintain web pages and components in LAMP-HTML-CSS-JQ-JS stacks for UI, SEO, SEM, email landing, business and corporate deliverables for YouSendIt.com.
- Resolved project and task issues for other company websites including Developer Portal.

Web/UI Developer | Fulltime Consultant | Verisign-Symantec Corporation (01/2011 – 08/2011)

- Worked daily as a Web team member with producers, designers and QA groups to update and maintain pages
- Troubleshot HTML/JS/CSS/PHP issues and resolved task/project tickets for Verisign.com, Geotrust.com, Thawte.com as well as the international websites in a LAMP environment.

Web Production Support Professional (XHTML/CSS/Javascript/Ajax & More) | Consultant – Extractable Solutions (10/2010-12/2010)

Completed projects with XHTML/CSS/Javascript/JQuery:

- Global primary navigation and drop-down menu functions with CSS
- Multiple-level Open/Close Navigation module functions with CSS
- Multiple tab module functions with CSS
- HTML5 Range module functions with CSS

Web Production Lead, Manager and Engineer/Developer | Extractable Solutions (04/2007 – 09/2010)

- Led, managed and mentored a team of front-end Web developers dedicated to supporting daily project and task development for Sun Microsystems (now Oracle)
- Converted raw documents from stakeholders to standalone HTML-compliant Web pages including header, breadcrumb, footer, meta, server-side script, CSS, Javascript, and related components
- Customized any given graphical elements to fit needs
- Applied meta info to graphical elements and Web pages
- Ran link reports for EndOfLife pages and updating links in the reported pages
- Assisted in updating new Java release notes in pages of 15 localized languages
- Implemented dynamic .jsp + .xml mechanisms for the recorded .pdf, .mp3 and .swf files for annual JavaOne event
- Implemented new theme designs to Roller blog site
- Implemented hosted videos via BrightCove
- Built data collection form via Data Collection system
- Set up Comments Registry for comments and ratings in articles
- Integrated associated components through Sun Information Architecture Management system
- Built dynamic tabbed hub mini sites (5 30+ pages) in .jsp following given IA wireframes
- Executed given editorial and/or creative content
- Established workflow processes
- Monitored all projects/tasks from initiation through delivery

Sites*: http://developers.sun.com, http://developers.sun.com, http://www.opensolaris.com, http://www

Server Environment: Java Server Pages (.jsp)

CMS: Interwoven Teamsite

Pages: HTML pages (.html), Teamsite template pages (.html and .xml) and Dynamic Java Server Pages (.jsp) Communication: Direct engagement with stakeholders in editorial, marketing and global publishing teams

* These websites have been integrated and migrated into the Oracle Technology Network using UCM (Oracle's CMS) (http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/java/index.html)

Other Implementation Projects outside of Sun/Oracle:

Nevada State Bank (Redesign): http://www.nsbank.com/

- Managed and developed complete production implementation including content entry (dynamic JSP site)

Netgear (CMS migration): http://www.netgear.com/

- Joined effort in content implementation and problem solving in SDL Tridion CMS

Red Prairie (Redesign): http://www.redprairie.com/

- Joined effort in content implementation and problem solving in Ektron CMS400.NET

Web Designer/Developer/Master/Manager | Lightwaves2020 Corporation (10/2006 – 03/2007)

- Developed, designed and managed the corporate website and content including Flash, templates, Web contact and product registration and newsletter subscription mechanisms

Sr. Web Designer/Developer/Master | eSignal - Interactive Data Corporation (04/2000 – 08/2006)

- Worked as a main contributor in the Marketing web team to develop, build, streamline & maintain core site structure, templates, UI, navigation, layout, HTML, Email Marketing, JavaScript, ASP, XML, and CSS of multiple marketing websites including graphical elements and interactive Flash tutorials.
- Contributed in the DNS, IIS, and SSL web server and replication system set up

Managing and Creative Director | Toto Images Advertising Agency (1996 – 2000)

- Managed all aspects of marketing campaigns including directive, collateral, videos and outreach for both the American and Chinese markets, as well as all office operations

Previous & Other Experiences (1976 – 1995)

Broadcast TV Producer and Director (World-wide Telecasting, Regular Programming, Documentaries)

Major Event Fundraiser and Organizer

Art Gallery Director and Exhibit Curator

Locations: San Francisco, Shanghai, Taipei

EDUCATION

Post-Graduate Learning | Various Training Institutions and Centers

Areas include: Web-related Production & Programming Technologies

MA, Creative Art | San Francisco State University, CA

AA, Visual Art with Award of Achievement | City College of San Francisco, CA

BE, Industrial Engineering | Chun-Yuan Christian University, Taiwan

Areas include: Computer Science, Human Factors, Motion and Time Study, Operations Research, System Analysis, Statistics, Industrial Psychology, Plant Layout and Management, Inventory Control, Marketing

PROFESSIONAL KNOWLEDGE / HANDS-ON EXPERIENCE / TOOLS

- Client-Side BOM/DOM: HTML5, CSS3, JS, JSON, XML, AJAX, etc.
- JS/CSS/Responsive Frameworks/Libraries: Node, NPM, Gulp, AngularJS(1.x), React, Underscore, Backbone, Express, jQuery, Dust, Mustache, Bootstrap, Foundation, Media Queries, SASS (Nested, Variables, Mixin, Include, Extend, etc.)
- Server-Side Technologies: PHP, JSP, ASP, ASPX, LAMP, WAMP, XAMPP, AMPPS, Apache, Tomcat, IIS, etc.
- Dev. Methodologies: Modularization of Components with Concepts of BEM, CSSOM, OOCSS, SMACSS, etc.
- Development Authoring Tools: Brackets, SublimeText, Notepad++, Visual Studio, VS Code, Netbeans IDE, Komodo, YUI Compressor, VI, Putty, Vimeo, YouTube, Camtasia, Sound Forge, QuarkXpress, Adobe CS (DW, Photoshop, Illustrator, Fireworks, Flash, InDesign, Premiere, AfterEffects), etc.
- Version Control: SVN, GIT, Tortoise SVN, SourceTree, etc.
- CMS: AEM(6.1&6.4), WordPress-Genesis-VisualComposer, Drupal, Lithium, Oracle RNT, CrafterRivet, Teamsite, Oracle UCM, CMS400.NET, SDL Tridion, etc.
- Marketing/Branding/Campaign/SEO/SEM: Site Pages, Email Marketing, Meta Keyword/Key Phrase/Description, Back links, Robot.txt, PageRank, Sitemap, Canonical Tag, Crawl Budget, Google Webmaster Tools Google Search Console, Adobe Target, Adobe Analytics, Google Analytics, WebTrends, etc.
- Database: MySQL + phpMyAdmin, MongoDB (Mongoose), MLab.
- System-Network-Protocols-Localization: i18n, CDN, DNS, SSH, FTP, SFTP, TCPIP, HTTPS, REST, Networking, Wireless Networking, etc.
- Scrum Tracking: JIRA, Rally, InVision, Confluence, Mantis, etc.

LANGUAGES: ENGLISH, MANDARIN, TAIWANESE, HAKKANESE